There are many things we remember from our childhood – the games we played, the music we listened to; but what about earning pocket money?
童年有很多值得我们回忆的东西——玩过的游戏、听过的音乐；但赚取零花钱的经历呢？
This was our first ever wage for completing tasks such as tidying our bedroom or sorting the laundry.
那是我们完成整理卧室、分拣衣物这类家务所获得的人生中第一份劳动报酬。
Our reward was a handful of coins that we safely stashed away.
我们会把得到的几枚硬币小心翼翼地存起来。
But now, it seems, parents’ attitude to handing out cash is changing.
但如今，父母们给孩子现金零花钱的态度似乎正在发生改变。
There was a time when cash was king – it was the main currency for financial transactions.
曾经有一段时期，现金为王——它是金融交易的主要支付方式。
These days, though, using credit or debit cards, or making contactless payments, are the most convenient ways of paying.
但如今，使用信用卡、借记卡或者非接触式支付，成了最便捷的付款途径。
So where does that leave handing over pocket money?
那么，这对现金零花钱的发放会产生什么影响呢？
Research has found that 84% of British parents currently give notes and coins to their children - typically an allowance, including some discretionary spending, of £7 a week.
研究发现，目前84%的英国家长仍会给孩子纸币和硬币作为零花钱，每周的金额通常为7英镑，其中包含一部分可自由支配的开支。
But banks predict that by 2028 only one in ten transactions will be with cash, and that it's something today’s children will have to deal with.
但银行预测，到2028年，只有十分之一的交易会使用现金，这是如今的孩子们未来必须面对的情况。
One particular issue is that children may not understand the value of cash because they never see it.
一个尤为突出的问题是，孩子们可能会因为从未接触过现金，而无法理解它的价值。
Parents face a dilemma too – finding a new way to transfer pocket money, or maybe not bothering to pay it at all.
家长们也面临着两难境地——要么寻找发放零花钱的新方式，要么干脆不再给孩子零花钱。
Giving children lessons about finance at school is important, and the UK’s Money and Pensions Service advises parents to get children started with money as young as possible.
在学校对孩子进行金融知识启蒙十分重要，英国货币与养老金服务机构建议家长尽早培养孩子的金钱观念。
Sarah Porretta from the service told the BBC that for parents who no longer carry cash “The trick is to go and get some coins, just so your children have the opportunity to interact with them.
该机构的萨拉·波雷塔向英国广播公司表示，对于那些不再随身携带现金的家长来说，“办法就是去兑换一些硬币，让孩子有机会接触它们。
Talk about what you are doing with money. If you are paying with a card or with a phone, talk to children about that and link it back to those coins they have handled."
和孩子聊聊你是如何使用金钱的，如果你用银行卡或手机支付，也要跟孩子解释清楚，并把这种支付方式和他们使用过的硬币联系起来。”
But, of course, many of the goods that young people want to buy – such as add-ons for a computer game – only allow digital transactions.
当然，年轻人想买的很多东西——比如电脑游戏的附加内容——只支持数字支付。
This has led to a number of apps being set up that allow children to track and spend their hard-earned pocket money and parents to transfer money electronically and monitor their child’s spending.
这催生了多款相关应用程序，孩子们可以通过这些应用记录和使用自己辛苦赚来的零花钱，家长则可以通过电子转账的方式发放零花钱，并监控孩子的消费情况。
Banks also suggest setting up accounts for older children which gives them a cash card to use.
银行还建议为年龄稍大的孩子开设账户，为他们办理现金卡。
But whatever method a parent chooses to adopt, they need to teach their kids that money doesn’t grow on trees!
但无论家长选择哪种方式，都需要告诉孩子：钱不是大风刮来的！